bizsugar.com 2019-06-28

# Small business news; tips; networking | BizSugar | Privacy Policy

**BIZSUGAR PRIVACY STATEMENT**

Our Responsible Privacy Practices 

Your privacy is important to us. 

At BizSugar, we take the collection of personal information seriously. The following Privacy Statement describes the types of personal information and anonymous information we receive and collect when you use and visit BizSugar, and how we safeguard your information. 

### Registering Your Account 

In order to become a BizSugar member, you must first register for an account on the Site. To register for an account, you are required to provide a chosen username and password and your email address. We do not make your email address and password publicly available and we strongly discourage you from doing so. 

Once a member, you may provide additional publicly accessible information in various areas of the Site, including the "Profile" area, chat rooms, message boards, comment areas, article submissions, etc. This includes describing yourself, your opinions and your personal contact information. Providing this type of personal information is entirely optional, and because we are unable to control how others may use such personal information, you do so at your own risk. 

In order to share story information with people you personally know who are not BizSugar members, you may enter their email addresses into our "tell a friend" or "email this" features. This information will be used by us to send a link directing them to this Site, including a message that you write. The email addresses of people that you invite will be used only to send your invitation. We may collect additional information from you if you sign up for our any of promotions or giveaways; enter, nominate, vote or attend any of our awards or contests; participate in any of our surveys, webcasts, mobile applications, tradeshows or other online or in-person events; or otherwise communicate or interact with our Site or services. 

### Electronic Communications

We communicate with you electronically through emails, newsletters and notices published on this Site. These include welcome emails, newsletters, promotional information, daily Site updates such as new content on the Site, and member communications to communicate important issues or changes about the Site, or perhaps to notify members that there has been a comment on one of their articles, etc. Our electronic communications may include the use of technologies such as single-pixel GIFs or other technologies to allow us to determine the number of people who open them. 

From time to time, we also offer downloadable content, contests, awards, surveys, webcasts, events and other online services on the Site and/or using email communication. 

Some email communications such as newsletters and special offers may track information for marketing purposes such as who or how many people opened an email or clicked on a link in an email. If you do not want your email activity to be tracked, then please do not opt in. 

From time to time our sponsors wish to contact our members who have indicated an interest in their products, services or events. If you register for products, services or events sponsored by a third-party, then you may receive communications directly from such third-parties. Their use of your information is subject to their privacy policies. 

You may opt-in to receive our electronic communications. You may remove yourself from receiving such services at any time. Any such electronic communication sent to you will include directions for how to unsubscribe. You may maintain your account with us and still opt out of receiving our newsletters, daily Site updates and/or promotions. However, if you wish to unsubscribe from our member communications, you will need to close your account. See the Choice/Opt-Out section below. 

### Traffic and RSS Data 

Like most other Internet sites, we track general Site traffic data such as the referring domains, browser type, time zone and other data. We also track statistics with respect to RSS, including the number of subscribers, type of RSS aggregators, and other data. We use such data and statistics to administer the Site, including managing comment spam, server loads, Site design requirements, and other administrative purposes. We also use aggregated traffic data and statistics for marketing analysis, determining future offerings, and other business uses. 

### Cookies, Web Beacons, Log Files (Clickstream)

We use Ezoic to provide personalization and analytic services on this website; as such Ezoic's privacy policy is in effect and can be reviewed [here](https://g.ezoic.net/privacy/bizsugar.com). 

Like most other Internet sites, we use cookies (small data files stored on your computer by your web browser upon visiting a website) to help you log in faster and enhance your navigation through the Site by storing information such as your personal preferences when you visit the Site. 

We use cookies in conjunction with web beacons (electronic files that signal when a webpage, advertisement, video, email, newsletter, etc., has been viewed) and similar technologies to collect clickstream data that helps us better understand how visitors move from page to page within our websites. The use of cookies and web beacons is anonymous and does not allow us to access personal information about you that you haven't already provided. 

Log file information is automatically reported by your browser each time you visit a web page. We collect and use data contained in log files. 

Through these various technologies we gather information such as your browser type, operating system, IP address, Internet Service Provider, mobile device identification number, the date and time when you visited the Site and which pages you viewed, which advertisements you clicked on, and whether you filled out an online form. 

We use your website activity to assist us in offering you a personalized web experience, assist you with technical support, diagnose problems with our server, administer our websites and tailor our service to you. In addition, we may work with third-party advertisers to target and serve advertising on the services or on third-party sites based on your preferences gleaned from such information. 

You may set your browser to block our cookies or third-party cookies. However, doing so may affect your ability to access services or programs (such as logging into accounts) on our Site and other websites. Some browsers may allow you to block certain web beacons and similar tracking codes. Please refer to your browser’s tools if you wish to block cookies, web beacons, etc. 

Deleting cookies does not mean you are permanently opted out of any advertising program. Unless you have settings that disallow cookies, the next time you visit a site running the advertisements, a new cookie will be added. 

### DoubleClick DART Cookies

We also may use DART cookies for Google’s DoubleClick advertising (including Google AdSense advertisements) to target and serve advertisements specific to your interests based on your browsing history. (For example, if you have been viewing sites about visiting Las Vegas, you may see Las Vegas hotel advertisements when viewing a non-related site, such as on a site about hockey). DART is not used to track your personal information. You can opt-out of this advertising service by visiting <http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/>

### Mobile Device Identifiers and Location Data

When you access the Site by a mobile device, we may collect identifiers that identify your mobile device and are used by us to enhance your use of the Site. A device identifier may remain on your device to help you log in faster and enhance your use of the services. We may also collect location data which may include information about the location of your mobile device. 

Device identifiers and location data may convey information to us about how you use the services. Some features of the services may not function properly if the use or availability of device identifiers and/or location data is disabled. 

### Use and Disclosure of Information by Us

We may use your personal information for several purposes, including sending you account notices; communicating with you about our services, events or products; providing you with additional information about the Site; providing you with information about products or services which we think may be of interest to you including targeted advertising regarding special offers, products, services and information; and measuring the effectiveness of advertisements on our Site. 

We may also use your personal information to do any of the following: (i) resolve disputes, collect fees, and troubleshoot problems; (ii) respond to specific inquiries made by you; (iii) enforce our [Terms of Service](http://www.bizsugar.com/page/terms); and (v) customize, measure, and improve our services, content, and layout. 

We may disclose or report your personal information if we, in our sole discretion, believe it is necessary or appropriate to do any of the following: (i) comply with the law or with legal process (e.g., a court order, subpoena, search warrant, or other legal process); (ii) protect our rights or the rights of a third-party; (iii) ensure the safety of the public or any person; (iv) respond to claims that any submission violates the rights of others; and (v) prevent or stop potentially prohibited or illegal activities. 

### Use and Collection of Information by Third-Parties

Third-parties (including advertisers, ad servers, ad networks, ad agencies, online targeting companies, data analytics partners, providers of widgets and applications, affiliates and sponsors) may use cookies, web beacons or similar technologies on the Site. 

Third-party advertisers featured in banner ads, sponsored posts, email newsletter blasts and other advertisements may solicit and collect personal information from you in order to provide advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to you, and to track your response to the advertisements. 

Third-party data analytics partners and online targeting companies may use anonymous information about your Internet traffic, which may result in remarketed/retargeted or other advertisements appearing on websites you visit or being sent to you based on your interests. 

As part of co-branded services or promotions with certain sponsors or business partners, we may request that you provide your personal information. We may share your information with our co-sponsor or business partner; or if your personal information is collected by our co-sponsor or business partner, they may share it with us. Information collected or used by a third-party is subject to that third-party’s own privacy policy, which is not within our control. 

### Privacy of Children

Children under the age of 18 are not permitted to register as a member on this service. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 18. If we become aware that a child under the age of 18 has provided us with personally identifiable information without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information from our database as quickly as possible. 

### Choice/Opt-Out

You have the opportunity to opt-in, opt-out or change your user preferences by: (i) emailing us at [[email protected]](https://share.bizsugar.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#2f4e4b4246416f4d46555c5a484e5d014c4042); (ii) editing the "Profile" area of your account; or (iii) clicking on a link in the footer of our electronic communications. Some communications (e.g., member communications about important account notifications) are necessary for all BizSugar members. You must close your BizSugar account to unsubscribe from these communications. To close your BizSugar account, put "close my account" in the subject line and email us at [[email protected]](https://share.bizsugar.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#ff9e9b929691bf9d96858c8a989e8dd19c9092). 

### Closure of Inactive Accounts

From time to time we may close inactive accounts without notice. An account will be deemed inactive if you opened the account but conducted no activity on the account for a period of thirty six (36) months. We do not retain personally identifiable information on inactive accounts. If you wish to conduct activity after an inactive account has been closed, please open a new account. 

### Security Precautions

We use reasonable precautions, including appropriate technical, administrative, and physical procedures, to protect personal information from loss, misuse, or alteration. We are not responsible for the effectiveness of security precautions of third-parties that provide us with services. 

Due to the design of the Internet and other factors outside our control, we cannot guarantee that communications between you and our servers will be free from unauthorized access by third-parties. 

### GDPR Consent 

For those individuals covered by GDPR: 

  * Consent to website cookies is obtained and managed through our partner, Ezoic, and more about this can be found at the Ezoic privacy policy for this Site, including instructions for how to manage privacy consent settings for this Site. [Go here](https://g.ezoic.net/privacy/bizsugar.com).
  * Email addresses and other information collected in connection with services and completing website forms is opt in. If you do not wish us to have your personal information, do not provide it to us. If you previously subscribed to email communications, you may unsubscribe using the unsubscribe link at the bottom of marketing emails. 
  * If you would like to review, correct, update, restrict or delete information previously provided in connection with the services, please contact us using the contact information below. In your request, please make clear what personal information you would like to review, correct, update, restrict or delete. For your protection, we will only fulfill requests for personal information associated with the email address you use to send your request, and we may otherwise require verification of your identity. 

### Notification of Changes 

This Privacy Statement may change from time to time and any changes will be published on the Site. The revised version will be effective as of the date and time it is published. Please check back periodically to be informed of any changes. 

### Contact

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, please email us at [[email protected]](https://share.bizsugar.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#96f7f2fbfff8d6f4ffece5e3f1f7e4b8f5f9fb) or write to us at: 

BizSugar.com  
ATTN: BizSugar Privacy Issues  
15275 Collier Blvd #201-367  
Naples, FL 34119 

Privacy Statement updated effective May 24, 2018.
